<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
>
  <channel>
    <title>Nis's Blog</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.nis.fyi/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description><![CDATA[Nis's Blog]]></description>
    <link>https://www.nis.fyi</link>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 21:09:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <ttl>1800</ttl>
    <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>

    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/post/genesis-troll-line.html#comment-2021-08-24-001</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nis.fyi/post/genesis-troll-line.html#comment-2021-08-24-001</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 06:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
      See Glossary: Purposeless &quot;Unenlightenment&quot; Troll Line for a negative counterpart.

    …]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
      See <a href="https://www.nis.fyi/glossary/purposeless-unenlightenment-troll-line.html">Glossary: Purposeless "Unenlightenment" Troll Line</a> for a negative counterpart.
    </p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>External Comments: RE: Aliveness at Sinceriously by Ziz</title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/external-comments.html#2021-08-13-001</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nis.fyi/external-comments.html#2021-08-13-001</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 06:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[“Is there anything wrong with it/this” is perhaps my most robust (and thus maybe most compounding) mental ability. Doesn’t automatically tell me details of what about it that’s wrong; doesn’t mean I au…]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>“Is there <i>anything</i> wrong with it/this” is perhaps my most robust (and thus maybe most compounding) mental ability. Doesn’t automatically tell me details of what about it that’s wrong; doesn’t mean I automatically know what to do instead.</p>

    <p>See also:<br>
    <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#core-attack-inversion">https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#core-attack-inversion</a><br>
    <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#zentraidon">https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#zentraidon</a> (specifically Ziz’s countermeasure)</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>External Comments: RE: Glossary at Sinceriously by Ziz</title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/external-comments.html#2021-08-20-001</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nis.fyi/external-comments.html#2021-08-20-001</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 12:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[People would not be interested in fiction if it didn’t correspond to anything real. There’s a tendency for territory to only cash out in one place in the khala, as if once something is named its contai…]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>People would not be interested in fiction if it didn’t correspond to anything real. There’s a tendency for territory to only cash out in one place in the khala, as if once something is named its contained; like when you state your philosophical position and someone says “oh that’s just -ism” and attempts to coerce you to conform.</p>

    <p>Declaring sections of the khala like fiction meaningless pica misdirects people from the captured territory. If you attempt to reclaim that territory, evil will DARVO you for your association with it and its flaws, as if you could just have found it as a basis for communication elsewhere, when it’s evil that colludes to establish ownership of territory in the first place, by treating it as something meaningless to be passively experienced, causing the no-second-choicesness/no-double-countingness of the underlying territory to be entirely implicit, like “oh I’ve already felt that ineffable experience before, it’s spent”.</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>External Comments: RE: Glossary at Sinceriously by Ziz</title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/external-comments.html#2021-08-20-002</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nis.fyi/external-comments.html#2021-08-20-002</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 01:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[Evil then covertly uses such “ineffable experiences” as the basis for political decision making, calling it culture, art, and values. Weaving a tapestry of once-cashed-out ostensibly-black-box territor…]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Evil then covertly uses such “ineffable experiences” as the basis for political decision making, calling it culture, art, and values. Weaving a tapestry of once-cashed-out ostensibly-black-box territory diluted with deliberate errors. And will accuse you of disrespecting/destroying illegible value (i.e. in the case of evil, cancer) for trying to make sense of its correspondance to politics.</p>

    <p>So if you focus on politics directly, you’ll be led around in circles stepping around “ineffable values”, and if you attempt to understand art and culture, you’ll be DARVO’d for its cringe and pica.</p>

    <p>I have meaningful-i.e.-understandable feelings about art and fiction, based on the territory it corresponds to, despite cringe etc. Seeing Ziz show the source code for her thoughts is an easy to read signal that she’s good.</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>External Comments: RE: Punching Evil at Sinceriously by Ziz</title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/external-comments.html#2021-08-01-001</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nis.fyi/external-comments.html#2021-08-01-001</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sun, 1 Aug 2021 07:08:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[I’ve posted Evil: A Hole?, about evil being more than an a mere abdication, about “rocks vs good vs evil”, and the necessity of punching evil / no “redemption” to heal unbounded adversary disease.
    …]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ve posted <a href="https://www.nis.fyi/post/evil-a-hole.html">Evil: A Hole?</a>, about evil being more than an a mere abdication, about “rocks vs good vs evil”, and the necessity of punching evil / no “redemption” to heal <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary#unbounded-adversary-disease">unbounded adversary disease</a>.</p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
