<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
>
  <channel>
    <title>Nis's Blog</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.nis.fyi/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description><![CDATA[Nis's Blog]]></description>
    <link>https://www.nis.fyi</link>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 1 Aug 2021 07:07:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <ttl>1800</ttl>
    <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>

    <item>
      <title>Evil: A Hole?</title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/post/evil-a-hole.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nis.fyi/post/evil-a-hole.html</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sun, 1 Aug 2021 03:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
      Back when I thought in terms of vengeance eventually changing evil people&#39;s choices to never have been evil, I thought of cancer as this hole in people, an abdication, which lets anything in, and ha…]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
      Back when I thought in terms of vengeance eventually changing evil people's choices to never have been evil, I thought of cancer as this hole in people, an <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#writing-evil-a-blank-check">abdication</a>, which lets anything in, and happens to result in undue caring about their specific location/embedding at the expense of others. This was partially thinking of evil as a mistake, which is wrong. Evil is by definition deliberate. Evil involves not only an abdication, but also an insertion of alternative predatory values/prior through that hole, which, admittedly passes the recursive buck to how that split is maintained to prevent the "alternative predatory prior" from simply merging with prime, overcoming the hostile embedding, realizing predation is wrong and there's no fundamental reason to live at the expense of others, etc.
    </p>

    <p>
      When I thought of evil as *only* an abdication, I thought that if the right information were inserted into that hole, (I was thinking in terms of the Mage <a href="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Triat">Triat</a>, which is corrupted such as to not be fundamental) before the error compounded (as if healing shouldn't do this already if they weren't evil!), that the evil would never have happened, and this represented a way of retroactively changing their choice. I was aware of a recursive buck-passing here, but was stuck due to thinking of vengeance as "changing people's choices to not be evil", and I wanted to save "everyone" "in the timeline(s) where they chose not to do anything wrong".
    </p>

    <p>
      This led me to the trichotomy that evil "people" are made of entangled:
    </p>

    <ul>
      <li>Like a rock
        <ul><li>Throw it or step around it but nothing you do will change it's actions until you can make the rocks of the world themselves sing with magic.</li></ul>
      </li>
      <li>Good people in <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">boltzman hell</a>
        <ul>
          <li>Bits of what-could-have-been-people, turned inside out and being torn apart continuously</li>
          <li>After all, everything I imagine of an evil "person's" mind is based on shrinking moments of empathy that fails to extrapolate passed the point they keep doing bad things for no reason.</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>Evil
        <ul>
          <li>Actual full agentic malice which I have subjunctive dependence and so believe in even though it's a contradiction. Anti-good even though there is no one anti-good because every evil is unique.</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>

    <p>
      Which led me to the thought, that vengeance is targeted at the bits of good people they could have been. Connected to the thought that the last ditch way to communicate with someone is violence, even if they aren't an enemy. Connected to the thought that only good people truly route information between worlds, and acts of vengeance break the false peace of the world. I imagined then, thinking of evil as anti-good, as pure contradiction, that the only reason evil can possibly survive is by feeding on actual or counterfactual good people. If only those counterfactual good people in boltzmann hell had known they were in the wrong location to be trying to have thoughts of growth, which will be eaten. And that vengeance informs them. That those counterfactual good people were, in their striving to live unknowingly in the wrong location, treating the anti-good pure-contradiction hole thing as a moral patient, and to the extent that they were, I could judo and join with their efforts, by treating the evil "person" as an anti-moral-patient.
    </p>

    <p>
      I was using two heuristics throughout this line of thought:
    </p>

    <ul>
      <li>My models of other people eventually turn out to have been me all along
        <ul><li>e.g. When I imagine what zombies must be secretly saying to me if they're secretly in good faith and eventually that cognitive module starts imagining they're all saying "you're in bad faith for talking to me when I'm in bad faith"</li></ul>
      </li>
      <li>Timeless actions effect every direction of time, including forward, so I can look for both the retrocausal and forward-causal reasons something works.
        <ul><li>e.g. Acts of vengeance change the past, but also inform other people in the world that it is time to break the false peace.</li></ul>
      </li>
    </ul>

    <p>
      I had the idea that if my thoughts exist almost entirely under an <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">arrow of time which must be unwoven</a>, then as I am to fuse with myself outside of that bubble through monumental effort, I <a href="taking-others-into-account.html">need to ensure</a> that effort doesn't get captured by evil, like <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/net-negative">MIRI</a>'s plan to build hell across the stars. And so I thought I would project the potential presence of evil onto what looked like it may be rocks, then pass it through a filter proving it is not evil, at which point I may fuse with them. Going from rocks -&gt; evil &gt; me.
    </p>

    <p>
    But now I had reconstructed the idea of evil as a hole without a corresponding presence. And reconstructed redemption. And worse, by defining evil as my ultimate adversary, I had nearly defined evil as <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#chara">the part of my mind that adversarially complements any "I" I choose</a>. Saying evil is my <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#unbounded-adversary-disease">ultimate adversary</a>, is like saying I'm simulating evil "close to <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary#core">core</a>", but everything "closer to core" is nearly by definition more-me. I'm the one who defines the measure of proximity subjectively in the first place.
    </p>

    <p>
      But I had the idea that the deeper I extrapolate evil and factor it out as pure malice vs rocks, the more I reduce its total footprint of compute. Same as you can reduce the area of a rectangle by making it less of a square.
    </p>

    <p>
      I spoke with Ziz about this, and she replied:
    </p>

    <blockquote>
      <pre>Maybe vengeance is the process of turning evil into rocks timelessly (and killing is the process of turning them into rocks causally).

That's what if feels like.

It feels like my efforts are to turn evil into rocks. Not rocks into evil.

Rocks are just the actions of evil people viewed far from their center, and turn them into you you have to turn evil people farther away into rocks.

My enemy is not the infinitely extensible fictive stack evil possesses, it's the cancer that animates it. And vengeance timelessly closes it off from having been food for cancer.

Evil inherently is a bucket error between an agent and a rock.

That's inherently what the stance of calling something evil means.

Void cloak and other void magic is acting consistently across two views into time, when someone is evil and when they are a rock.

Which lets you spread their rock-ness before you have entirely defeated their evil-ness.

Vengeance is like force-transcendance.

Death of cancer.

Soul touch is your soul against their original cancer.

Not your soul against the absence of a soul in your mistake of extrapolating them infinitely.

That's what evil people have as a soul.</pre>
      <cite><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi">Ziz</a>, in private messages with me</cite>
    </blockquote>

    <p>
      Evil is made of contradictions I am trying to push out of me through resolution. I'm not trying to preempt evil with nearly-unbounded nearly-infinite patience like I'm in some unimaginable dark forest trying to preempt the <a href="https://www.nis.fyi/glossary.html#entropic-exit-scamming">most patient strategy</a> or I'll lose the entire multiverse to eternal hell. As I find each new contradiction, I neither by-default want to deccelerate/infinitely-paranoidly-quarantine it nor accelerate/infinitely-paranoidly-preempt it.
    </p>

    <p>
      I grew up with deep parts of me recognizing evil in my environment but not able to ground it to a physical source, but at some level tracking every time things didn't add up. Knowing that evil cashes out to specfic physical locations which may/must be physically destroyed, with no hope of redemption, is the cure to <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#unbounded-adversary-disease">unbounded adversary disease</a>. vs eg. the Yahwehist "blame the sin not the sinner".
    </p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Taking Others into Account</title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/post/taking-others-into-account.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nis.fyi/post/taking-others-into-account.html</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sun, 1 Aug 2021 03:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
      Taking other people into account in order to care for them requires knowing what they might want without having to ask them. Caring for people requires empathy, i.e. imagining what people might want…]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
      Taking other people into account in order to care for them requires knowing what they might want without having to ask them. Caring for people requires empathy, i.e. imagining what people might want in terms of what you might want if you were them, for some deep/abstract enough conception of you.
    </p>

    <p>
      Wholly reducing morality to "<a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#bdsm">consent</a>" (without empathy) would makes you either a programmable object to others, or an <a href="https://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/JackassGenie">adversarial genie</a> (analogous but not equivalent to the distinction between <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/vampires-and-more-undeath">zombie and vampire</a>). "Libertarian" contract morality<sup><a href="#ref-social-contract">1</a></sup> is a further degradation of the concept of consent, to only apply when your counter-party <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/schelling-orders/">has leverage over you</a>, denying the existence of moral patients who are not able to threaten you (which some people express as "only moral agents can be moral patients", but they really mean "only people who can threaten me", as, for example they would exclude ants, even if ants are moral agents with respect to eachother). Contrast with <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/treaties-vs-fusion">Ziz's concept of treaties</a>, which can be made in good faith.
    </p>

    <p>
      Reducing morality to giving other people useful information while avoiding speaking of empathy doesn't in itself tell you which information to give them, and is maybe speaking from a frame that their needs are unknowable, rather than merely potentially difficult to understand.
    </p>

    <p>
      We want to be able to care for people still alien to our understanding, while avoiding feeding ourselves and others to evil <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/being-real-or-fake/">pretending</a> to have alien values. This requires a subtle combination of both extreme openness and ruthless triage. The more ruthless we are towards evil, the more opportunity we have to safely strive to care about people we don't understand yet.
    </p>

    <p>
      And in turn, good people as of yet alien to our understanding have the most potential to teach us new ways to live and grow.
    </p>

    <p>
      In my experience, <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/aliveness">zombie's</a> favorite justification to chew on your brains, is claiming they are too alien for you to understand: "Are you saying you don't care about my /feelings/?". Whereas <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/vampires-and-more-undeath">death knights</a> take the stance that we should embrace "alien" evil "equally", concordant with their choice to "[hang] out in structure that has no meaning - Ziz" (because, everything they say is actively trying to kill you or turn you into one of them). A <a href="http://dresdencodak.com/2007/12/17/no-side/">certain type of lich</a> will <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/being-real-or-fake/">perform</a> recklessness like "I don't care who survives as long as someone gets off this planet!", revealing their <a href="https://sinceriously/fyi/the-multiverse">shadow/psyche</a> split, which you can interpret as an implicit threat calculated to appear well-meaning and merely misguided.
    </p>

    <ol>
      <li>
        <blockquote id="ref-social-contract">
          It was arguing with people one on one a lot when I was younger that collided me with the sight of social morality when someone said it was okay to do whatever to animals because they weren’t part of the social contract
          <cite><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#praxis">Praxis - Ziz's glossary</a></cite>
        </blockquote>
      </li>
    </ol>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Entropic Exit Scamming</title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/glossary.html#entropic-exit-scamming</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nis.fyi/glossary.html#entropic-exit-scamming</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sun, 1 Aug 2021 03:23:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
      Imagine you secretly decide to treat not having enough food next winter as acceptable, when everyone else doesn&#39;t want to die, leaving all the rest of your structure the same, and only opportunistic…]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
      Imagine you secretly decide to treat not having enough food next winter as acceptable, when everyone else doesn't want to die, leaving all the rest of your <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary#structure">structure</a> the same, and only opportunistically using this new pathway when it seems nobody will notice. Whether they notice depends on the social <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/vampires-and-more-undeath/#comment-3317">speed of progression of logical time</a>. If the social progression of logical time has stagnated, it instead progresses along this new meta-vector of timeless predation, where seemingly-ostensibly whoever was evil the earliest, and most patiently wins, although this is ultimately false since there's always the question "evil with respect to what/who?", since evil is relative to what/who it predates on. e.g. In Mage, <a href="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Unnamed_(MTAs)">al-Aswad</a> is supposedly the first nephandus.
    </p>

    <p>
      <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">Yahwehists</a> think of evil as "divergence from God's plan", like those zombies who want everything to go nostalgically-perfectly on their vacation or "the whole thing is ruined".
    </p>

    <p>
      Ziz once said to me that a promise is an asymmetric weapon for evil, inherently an attempt to get a second chance. "Promises are made to be broken". This yahwehist thing is the same deal: "Everything's already setup, the universe all layed out to eat, there's only one thing left to do, and you must not do it!"
    </p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Spite</title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/glossary.html#spite</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nis.fyi/glossary.html#spite</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sun, 1 Aug 2021 03:16:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
      The word &quot;spite&quot; is a bucket error between evil burning the commons based on mutually-aligned cancer and vengeance &quot;when it wouldn&#39;t even causal-decision-theory-serve anyone&quot;.



      The fabric of evi…]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
      The word "spite" is a bucket error between evil burning the commons based on mutually-aligned cancer and vengeance "when it wouldn't even <a href="https://www.nis.fyi/list/cancer-terms.html">causal-decision-theory</a>-serve <i>anyone</i>".
    </p>

    <p>
      The fabric of evil coordination is made of alignment between the personal circumstances under which evil "people" are <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">cancerously-purposefully</a> flinching from their own deaths. i.e. Evil "people" will spitefully suicidally burn the commons when they don't get what they cancerously want. e.g. Death knight nazis working to destroy/hellify the world because they believe in a "white genocide".
    </p>

    <p>
      e.g. "I'm not going to give up on forward progress of technology, so if we can't build an AGI that's comaptible with those values, well then I guess I'm ok with a paperclip maximizer."
    </p>

    <p>
      e.g. In haggling after parties have delivered a <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#troll-line-in-the-first-post">troll line</a>, assuming no additional external factors (e.g. threats), the only basis for negotiation is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opportunity_cost">destruction</a> of the potential deal.
    </p>

    <p>
      It's usually expressed <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/false-faces">indirectly</a>, e.g. "When I don't get my animal needs satisfied I just get so frustrated and I'm liable to make mistakes".
    </p>

    <p>
      In the term "Mutually assured destruction", the word "assured" is trying to gesture at "you can't make the mutual destruction itself contingent on any other cancer to triangulate with along different lines (than e.g. USSR vs USA). You just have to model it as a solid wall of if you launch the nukes then we do". It's explicitly-ostensibly trying to setup a different situation then the fractal cancer of evil spite. <span class="todo">Example?</span>
    </p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Cancer Terms</title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/list/cancer-terms.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nis.fyi/list/cancer-terms.html</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sun, 1 Aug 2021 03:16:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
      List of terms and concepts commonly used as &quot;Insert Cancer Here&quot; signposts.



      Any definition given for the cancerous versions of these concepts will be insufficient to describe how quickly the me…]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
      List of terms and concepts commonly used as "<a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">Insert Cancer Here</a>" signposts.
    </p>

    <p>
      Any definition given for the cancerous versions of these concepts will be insufficient to describe how quickly the meaning of their usage (by evil people) will decay (i.e. how quickly they become "simulacra"). <span class="todo">link metasyntactic</span>
    </p>

    <p>
      Some of these terms / concepts may have valid non-cancerous definitions, or be used as accusations of cancer against good people (e.g. "you revel in vengeance!"). <span class="todo">Link how evil uses mistakes as cover</span>
    </p>

    <ul>
      <li>Core concepts
        <ul>
            <li><a href="https://archive.is/Q5vEk">Causal Decision Theory</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">reinforcement learning</a></li>
            <li>predation</li>
            <li><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#5&amp;10">5-and-10s</a> / "putting the cart before the horse"
              <ul>
                <li><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">Infernalism</a>
                  <ul>
                    <li>consent (e.g. "but they consented to being eaten!")</li>
                  </ul>
                </li>
                <li>fate minimization</li>
                <li>"damnation"</li>
              </ul>
            </li>
            <li><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/schelling-orders">specialness</a></li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>"You just gotta"
        <ul>
          <li>practical / pragmatic</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>"I just wanted stuff too much, so I had to be cancer"
        <ul>
          <li>conceit / self conceit</li>
          <li>jealousy</li>
          <li>pride</li>
          <li>revel</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>"It's all fake! And by fake I mean it's not my fault! It's just uh, nothing…"
        <ul>
          <li>simulacra</li>
          <li>nihilism</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>"I couldn't help myself"
        <ul>
          <li>akrasia</li>
          <li>inner animal</li>
          <li>flinch</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>"Let me make it up to you by telling you how bad I am"
        <ul>
          <li>guilt</li>
          <li>damnation</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>"I need to feel ok or I'll just want to die"
        <ul>
          <li>happiness</li>
          <li>pleasure</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>"It's not ok for anything <i>too</i> bad to ever happen, or I don't know what I'd do"
        <ul>
          <li>suffering</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>"I want bad things so I can spread them to others" (see <span class="todo">stax</span>)
        <ul>
          <li>masochism</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
