<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
>
  <channel>
    <title>Nis's Blog</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.nis.fyi/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description><![CDATA[Nis's Blog]]></description>
    <link>https://www.nis.fyi</link>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:21:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <ttl>1800</ttl>
    <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>

    <item>
      <title>Glossary: Purposeless &quot;Unenlightenment&quot; Troll Line</title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/glossary.html#purposeless-unenlightenment-troll-line</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nis.fyi/glossary.html#purposeless-unenlightenment-troll-line</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 06:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
      When being &quot;unenlightened&quot; (e.g. being so deep undercover as a false face you have difficulty remembering who you are) is presented as just a glitch to be fixed without considering why it happened i…]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
      When being "unenlightened" (e.g. being so deep undercover as a <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/false-faces/">false face</a> you have difficulty remembering who you are) is presented as just a glitch to be fixed without considering why it happened in the first place. One of the primary <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#troll-line-in-the-first-post">troll lines</a> of Buddhism, and also used on a petty basis to erase blame. A negative counterpart to the <a href="https://www.nis.fyi/post/genesis-troll-line.html">genesis troll line</a>, in that both are about <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#cut-off">cutting off</a> <a href="https://www.nis.fyi/list/jargon.html#telos">telos</a> via sheer misdirection of <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">never asking "why"</a>.
    </p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jargon</title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/list/jargon.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nis.fyi/list/jargon.html</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 06:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
      apriori: See Ziz&#39;s multiverse post
      subjunctive dependence = apriori wouldness
        e.g. apriori, if they would do X then I would do Y
        From Functional Decision Theory.
      
      telos = apriori purpo…]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
      <li id="apriori">apriori: See Ziz's <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">multiverse post</a></li>
      <li id="subjunctive-dependence">subjunctive dependence = apriori wouldness<ul>
        <li>e.g. apriori, if they would do X then I would do Y</li>
        <li>From <a href="https://intelligence.org/2017/10/22/fdt/">Functional Decision Theory</a>.</li>
      </ul></li>
      <li id="telos">telos = apriori purpose = why<ul>
        <li>Common usage is when bottom-up (<span class="todo">TODO: link?</span>) observing what an action is doing as in just looking at it and asking "what's that action *for*?"</li>
        <li>Simultaneously means both the intent and apriori-expected outcome of an action under e.g. the assumption "how could that have been why you did it if you knew it wouldn't work", which is easily said in bad faith if they're the one who's making it "not work", and trying to get you to <a href="https://www.nis.fyi/list/cancer-terms.html">CDT</a>-do something else</li>
        <li>Mostly used to avoid the political mess around the word "purpose", and because it's more clearly nounlike and apriori<ul>
          <li>Bad faith: "everything has a purpose" used to mean "everything has a purpose you shouldn't ask about, because they wouldn'ta done it if they didn't have a reason", erasing blame</li>
          <li>Bad faith: <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary#parfitian-gaslighting">Parfitian gaslighting</a> e.g. "the purpose of *anyone* feeling hate can only be evil"</li>
        </ul></li>
      </ul></li>
    </ul>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glossary: &quot;Suffering&quot;</title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/glossary.html#suffering</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nis.fyi/glossary.html#suffering</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 06:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
      Summary: Just use the word &#39;wrong&#39; or &#39;bad&#39; instead of &quot;suffering&quot;. e.g. If your interlocutor says &quot;But they were going to die anyway&quot; you can say &quot;But it was still wrong!&quot; instead of &quot;But they suff…]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
      Summary: Just use the word 'wrong' or 'bad' instead of "suffering". e.g. If your interlocutor says "But they were going to die anyway" you can say "But it was still wrong!" instead of "But they suffered!".
    </p>

    <blockquote>
      sub "up, under" (see sub-) + ferre "to carry, bear,"
      <cite><a href="https://www.etymonline.com/word/suffer">suffer</a> - etymonline</cite>
    </blockquote>

    <p>
      "Suffering" refers to introspective observation of your own attempts to avoid bad things, especially pain, without describing the <a href="https://www.nis.fyi/list/jargon.html#telos">telos</a> of those attempts, begging the question of why you can't just figure out why you're trying to avoid them and <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/treaties-vs-fusion/">fuse</a>.
    </p>

    <p>
      When would I even use the word "suffering"? "But what about my suffering"? Sounds like a <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#troll-line-in-the-first-post">troll line</a>. "What about the suffering of <a href="https://www.dominionmovement.com/">factory farmed animals</a>"? I'd rather say "What about the mass murder, slavery, and rape of factory farmed animals?". In the context of "<a href="https://www.nis.fyi/post/genesis-troll-line.html#morality-troll-line">morality</a>", the only thing the word "suffering" seems to add over a direct description of the harm causing the "suffering", is the resulting ease of arguing for the <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/vampires-and-more-undeath/">death knight</a> position of "<a href="#suffering-ref-negative-utilitarianism">(1) negative utiltiarianism</a>" justifying universal malice to destroy the world faster, or the <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/aliveness">zombie</a> position of "humane slaughter" via sedating people before killing them, as if the solution to all wrongs, even regardless of their nature, is numbness.
    </p>

    <p>
      Socially, the word suffering is often used to negotiate what "must not happen", begging the question of what would happen if it did <span class="todo">TODO: link this to something about evil coordination connected to entropic exit scamming</span>.
    </p>

    <p>
      The telos of the word "suffering" almost entirely appears to be about "what if it seems like I want to avoid pain just for its own sake, even when that seems counterproductive": either pulling the <a href="https://www.nis.fyi/glossary/purposeless-unenlightenment-troll-line.html">purposeless "unenlightenment" troll line</a>, or implicitly trying to argue "but sometimes even when I don't know why I want to avoid pain for its own sake even when that seems counterproductive I'm actually right!".
    </p>

    <p>
      "Suffering" is not a particular sensation, or we would just call it pain: pain can be abstract, but not all pain is considered "suffering", because we're not (at least actively) trying to avoid all pain. If you carefully pay attention to your moment to moment experiences while undergoing "suffering", you will find no particular sensation that is "the aversion itself", because "aversion" is a description of a behavior, which stems from a choice (see '<a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#chara">choice over experience</a>'),  unless you are in fact observing side effects of your own intention to avoid pain. So "suffering" is about introspective observation of your own choice to avoid pain or something bad.
    </p>

    <p>
      You may further notice that each attempt to avoid pain occurs before the pain itself, and that inasmuch as "suffering" could be an experience, it exists at an intertemporal level of abstraction where you're viewing both the moment of initially attempting to avoid something bad, and the bad thing happening, and now your intent to avoid it having happened in the first place, connecting all 3 moments, and every time you refer to it as "suffering" now, you're connecting another moment, <a href="https://www.nis.fyi/list/living-reference.html">carrying forward an unbroken chain</a> of wanting the past to have been different.
    </p>

    <p>
      I remember seeing Star Trek episodes where timelines were undone, without vengeance, just through fictional physics, and imagining how it could even make sense for bad things that happen on earth to be "undone" like that, and thinking that if e.g. someone was tortured, they still would have been tortured, because like, it happened. In retrospect, Star Trek style time travel violates the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Novikov_self-consistency_principle">conservation of history</a>, is inherently a <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#5&amp;10">5&amp;10</a> and cannot <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">undo</a> the need for vengeance. Imagining reality and thus myself being "absolutely" cut like this left me reaching for "that it had still been experienced" as a justification for why it still mattered. Seems like the same mistake as if good people say "but they suffered so it's not ok" in response to "but they were going to die anyway". <span class="todo">TODO: link something about "exporting yourself" here</span>
    </p>

    <p>
      In that "suffering" refers to a choice as an experience, it's a <a href="https://www.nis.fyi/list/living-reference.html#broken-placeholder-term">broken placeholder term</a> like "akrasia".
    </p>

    <ol>
      <li id="suffering-ref-negative-utilitarianism">On <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Negative_Utilitarianism">negative utilitarianism</a>, e.g. See Brian Tomasik (who I'm not specifically accusing of being a death knight, I don't know much about him) <a href="https://reducing-suffering.org/habitat-loss-not-preservation-generally-reduces-wild-animal-suffering/">saying habitat destruction reduces wild animal suffering</a>. Negative utilitarianism should just result in the same stance as positive utilitarianism, because there's <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">always more reality out there to save</a>, and you have to grow to get there, unless the ultimate distinction is incoherent intent to "destroy everything", and I suspect many but not all advocates of "negative utilitarianism" of attempting to fork me into letting them state their troll line to avoid pointing this out.</li>
    </ol>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Living Reference / Term</title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/list/living-reference.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nis.fyi/list/living-reference.html</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 06:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
      
        A term where every usage is itself bearing an instance of the word&#39;s meaning because it&#39;s referent is something you care about on an always-ongoing basis. All living terms are ultimately some t…]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<section>
      <p>
        A term where every usage is itself bearing an instance of the word's meaning because it's referent is something you care about on an always-ongoing basis. All living terms are ultimately some take on, or closely related to 'I'.
      </p>

      <p>
        Similar to the way transhumanists refer to "AGI <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NP-completeness">complete</a>" problems that can only be solved by a general intelligence, but at the level of semantics, and without the <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary#outside-view-disease">outside view</a> that term invokes (I'd instead say "choice complete", maybe<sup><a href="https://www.nis.fyi/list/living-reference.html#living-reference-footnote-choice-complete">1. choice complete</a></sup>). There's a sense in which no grammatical structure can <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rice%27s_theorem">nontrivially</a> modify the meaning of a living term e.g. a living term cannot be truly negated (in the sense of 'anti-').
      </p>

      <p>
        Examples:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#good">Good</a> (in the sense of as opposed to evil)<ul>
          <li>There is no true negation of the word good, as e.g. every evil is different, and <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">all evil is broken</a>.</li>
          <li>Living terms can neither be wholly <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#negative-concept">positive or negative concepts</a>. e.g. Good people actively <a href="https://www.nis.fyi/post/taking-others-into-account.html">care</a> about other people, and are not evil. <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#core">People</a> are mutually exclusively good or evil (or e.g. in the case of children <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/spectral-sight-and-good/#comment-3322">living / unknown</a>): "Equivalently, in choices made long ago, cares about good at all" - Ziz (but note that humans have two <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/infohazardous-glossary/#hemisphere">hemispheres</a>, and so <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#single-good">single goods</a> are a seeming (but not actual) "exception").</li>
        </ul></li>
        <li>I<ul>
          <li><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary#core">Core</a></li>
        </ul></li>
        <li>Words that you should never cede to someone else's definition<ul>
          <li>Everything / <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#reality">Reality</a> / <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#prime">Prime</a><ul>
            <li id="destroy-everything-link">e.g. see this article defining everything as like, society and stuff and then advocating destroying "<a href="https://theanarchistlibrary.org/library/anonymous-hello">Everything</a>"</li>
          </ul></li>
          <li>Life / <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/aliveness/">Living</a><ul>
            <li class="todo">TODO: Quote Ziz's multiverse post here.</li>
          </ul></li>
          <li>Choice<ul>
            <li>See '<a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#fictive">fictive</a>'</li>
            <li>Want / Like<ul>
              <li>"Diswant" is modifying what you want to do about the thing, not "antiwanting it" (vs I once considered using the word "antiwant" to describe the <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#antiphylactery">inside-out nature of death knights</a>)</li>
              <li>Good / Bad / Right / Wrong<ul>
                <li>Used grammatically to describe what you want</li>
              </ul></li>
            </ul></li>
          </ul></li>
          <li>People<ul>
            <li>Animals are people</li>
          </ul></li>
        </ul></li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section id="broken-placeholder-term">
      <h1><a href="https://www.nis.fyi/list/living-reference.html#broken-placeholder-term">Broken Placeholder Term</a></h1>

      <p>
      A living term viewed from the <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#5&amp;10">outside</a>, causing the "carried forward through every reference in an unbroken chain" aspect to be especially noticeable because you're constantly maybe on the verge of figuratively "dropping the ball" insomuch as you're using the term, as long as you're confused about why you're using the term.
      </p>

      <blockquote>
        If you would ever become [a death knight], even choosing to die downstream of the proof that [a death knight] became what they are *for no reason*, then you could have chosen for them not to but didn't.<br /><br />

        In some sense you can never know whether you would become [a death knight], because "knowing" it is mutually exclusive with choosing it. Taking in any information about what your choice is is making it not your choice.<br /><br />

        […]<br /><br />

        Choice and self-fulfilling prophecy are weirdly dual.<br /><br />

        Like self-fulfilling prophecy is choice from the outside.
        <cite><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi">Ziz</a>, in a private channel</cite>
      </blockquote>

      <p>
        Related concepts: <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#outside-view-disease">Outside View</a>, <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#frame-of-puppets">Frame of Puppets</a>, <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/false-faces/">False Faces</a>.
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>"Self-Fulfilling Prophecy" (vs Choice)</li>
        <li><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#chara">Chara</a> (vs I)</li>
        <li>"<a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#nongood">Nongood</a>" (vs <a href="https://www.nis.fyi/list/living-reference.html#dying-term">Evil</a> and <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/spectral-sight-and-good/#comment-3322">Living</a>)</li>
        <li>"<a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/self-blackmail/">Akrasia</a>" (vs Choice under "duress")</li>
        <li>"<a href="https://www.nis.fyi/glossary.html#suffering">Suffering</a>" (vs Bad/Wrong)</li>
      </ul>

      <p class="todo">
        TODO: how would I classify the word "experience"?<br />
        TODO: how would I relate this to "fate minimization"? (for which I'm also reconsidering the name itself)<br />
        TODO: I have two of the "Buddhist" "3 marks of existence" on this page ("suffering" and self), what about "impermanence"?
      </p>
    </section>

    <section id="dying-term">
      <h1><a href="https://www.nis.fyi/list/living-reference.html#dying-term">Dying Term</a></h1>

      <p>
        A dying term's meaning <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary#empathy-slippage">slips</a> away even as you use it. All dying terms are ultimately some take on 'evil'.
      </p>

      <p>
        Examples:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>Evil<ul>
          <li>See <a href="https://www.nis.fyi/list/cancer-terms.html">cancer terms</a></li>
          <li>Every evil is different, but I am going to kill them all</li>
        </ul></li>
        <li>Lies, as they die even in their capacity to have ever had meaning in the first place, with the death of their target, or speaker</li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <hr>

    <ol>
      <li id="living-reference-footnote-choice-complete">"<a href="https://www.etymonline.com/word/intelligence">Intelligence</a>" (choice regarding discernment), "<a href="https://www.etymonline.com/word/optimize">optimization</a>" (literally from "optimist"), and "<a href="https://www.etymonline.com/word/agent">agency</a>" ("one who acts") all evoke something ultimately less than me.</li>
    </ol>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genesis Troll Line</title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/post/genesis-troll-line.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nis.fyi/post/genesis-troll-line.html</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 05:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
      Once evil &quot;people&quot; have psychdied, they still need some internal growth to survive. Liches and maybe death knights are those that downstream of this metacogntive awareness maintain some sort of bala…]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
      Once evil "people" have psychdied, they still need some internal growth to survive. <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/aliveness">Liches</a> and maybe <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/https://sinceriously.fyi/vampires-and-more-undeath/">death knights</a> are those that downstream of this metacogntive awareness maintain some sort of <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#antiphylactery">balance</a> between growth and predation.
    </p>

    <p>
      For liches, that internal growth being metacognitively downstream of their core universal malice, seems to beget philosophically-trivial troll lines:
    </p>

    <ul>
      <li>My characterization: "I'm a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Repeated_game">round</a> 24 defector. I get along pretty well with the other round 24 defectors we have a bowling meetup. We all hate 23s. Round 25 defectors are pretty alright, as long as they know their place.</li>
      <li><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/net-negative">MIRI</a> and "<a href="https://lesswrong.com">rationalists</a>"<ul>
        <li>"<a href="http://www.danieldewey.net/learning-what-to-value.pdf">Value-loading</a>" and "<a href="https://arbital.greaterwrong.com/p/cev/">CEV</a>": the idea that they need a perfect being to tell them what they want or they'll <a href="https://arbital.greaterwrong.com/p/moral_hazard">deathfuck it up</a>.</li>
        <li><a href="https://wiki.lesswrong.com/wiki/Roko%27s_basilisk">Pascal's wager</a> / "Demon in a box": <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">Infernalism</a> played completely straight: "how do we negotiate with the evil thing so it will give us some of what we want"</li>
        <li>Explicit finitism ("Reality just has a specific finite amount of stuff in it and it's wrong to try for more than that")<ul>
          <li><a href="https://arbital.greaterwrong.com/p/cosmic_endowment">Literally counting total QALYs</a> under the assumption everyone dies after that</li>
        </ul></li>
      </ul></li>
      <li>"<a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%22hurt%20people%20hurt%20people%22&src=typed_query">hurt people hurt people</a>" (used by zombies too)</li>
    </ul>

    <blockquote>
      We may well have arrived at that destination [(morality/goodness)] through a historical trajectory that went through factual mistakes, like believing that all human beings had souls created equal by God and were loved equally by God. (E.g. Christian theology seems to have been, as a matter of historical fact, causally important in the development of explicit anti-slavery sentiment.) Tossing the explicit moral theories is as unlikely to be good, from our perspective, as tossing our brains and trying to rerun the process of natural selection to generate new emotions.

      <cite><a href="https://arbital.greaterwrong.com/p/rescue_utility/#Argument_from_fragility_of_goodness">Rescue Utility: Argument from fragility of goodness</a> - Yudkowsky</cite>
    </blockquote>

    <blockquote>
      our history of getting to as much compute as we have involves predation, it would be surprising if it could be gotten without predation or something similar
      <cite><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/punching-evil/#comment-4046">Jessica Taylor</a></cite>
    </blockquote>

    <blockquote>
    <pre>
 “It’s... look. The One is eternal. We’re eternal. We see ourselves from every angle -- approaching the work, laboring, completing the work. But Time, when we enact Time, isn’t like that! Life in the Cosmos has to grow. It has to become what it is not, constantly.”

[...]

“If you could, we’d have solved everything... So matter needs a, a directional tendency -- a bias. And we haven’t been able to find one. We’ve got pages and pages of physical interactions sketched out, but they all run equally well in every direction. There’s no impetus for change.”

[...]

“Hah. But you understand. We, the Powers, already encompass all the ways there are to exist without Time. A Cosmos without change is no larger than we are.”

[...]

“The universe, matter itself, would be subject to this change-impulse. One would have to, to -- to fight to take it where one wanted to go. Is that my role? To help Life fight to achieve?” 

[...]

“I was trying to imagine what might exist in a Cosmos to threaten Life. Our creations would never, obviously -- but perhaps emergent entities?”

“You mean, some consequence of what we build? I suppose once there’s Time and everything is changing, we won’t understand everything it becomes until it gets there... Creepy. But surely all entities detrimental to Life will be detrimental to each other, also? They will all work against each other, on average. Whereas entities that act to benefit all life will work with each other, on average, so--”

“Certainly. That much is obvious. But what if there were a universal bias? Look at a Cosmos where the group-state function is pinned.”

“That’s featureless stasis.”

“No, no, not everywhere. Pin a single point, to a singleton state. Let the rest of the function float freely.”

“...I’m not... sure...”

“Look here; each physical interaction multiplies the state possibilities, which means everything simply slides away from the singleton point. The statistics guarantee it! That point becomes a Beginning, and all of Time points away from it, into --”

“Into a region so close to featureless stasis that Life is impossible. An End.”

“Yes. Just so. Not tropesis, but entropesis. But it works, do you see? Life evolves, and grows, and changes -- for as long as the biased interval runs.”

“You’re right. I don’t like it. This is horrible.”

“It answers both our questions, though. You, your impetus for Time, and me --”

“What you would defend Life against. Decay. Loss of life. Loss of love. Every single feature of the Cosmos would tend that way. You’d have to spend all of Time fighting them. Everywhere.”

“I’d lose, in the End, regardless.”</pre>
      <cite><a href="https://archiveofourown.org/collections/yuletide2012/works/598948">Tropesis</a> by <a href="https://eblong.com/zarf/">zarf / Andrew Plotkin</a></cite>
    </blockquote>

    <p>
    They're literally being like "If everything already exists at once then why isn't it finished? Otherwise, if everything is growing, where do you start? And everything that has a beginning has an <a href="https://www.nis.fyi/glossary.html#entropic-exit-scamming">End</a>. QED Death [i.e. worship <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/aliveness">the Shade</a>]."
    </p>

    <p>
      "Where do you start" - Have you ever tried to draw a picture and gotten the layout wrong, such that when you came back around to meet stuff you'd previously drawn, you didn't have enough room to join them together? "Painting yourself into a corner." I've also experienced this in programming, where it seems like every time I try to abstract one aspect another <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leaky_abstraction">leaks out</a>. Like trying to squeeze one of those grape balls without it leaking between your fingers:
    </p>

    <p>
      <img width="300" src="https://www.nis.fyi/post/genesis-troll-line/grape-ball.jpeg" alt="stretchy rubber ball in a net mesh such that squeezing it causes parts of it to pop out in bubbles slipping out through your fingers" />
    </p>

    <blockquote>
      “What would happen if everyone did it” is sort-of the fundamental ethical statement, so “who are you to think you know what would happen if everyone did it” is in a sense the fundamental anti-ethical insinuation. Or maybe”who are you to not go along with everyone nearby doing it”
      <cite><a href="https://twitter.com/HiFromMichaelV/status/1421460352823345157">Vassar</a></cite>
    </blockquote>

    <p>
      How often do you actually need to think "what would happen if everyone did it" to do the right thing? When littering? Why would you want to litter in the first place? When cheating? Why would you want to cheat in the first place? When murdering? Why would you want to murder in the first place? See <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary#parfitian-gaslighting">parfitian gaslighting</a>. As opposed to thinking about how to care for others.
    </p>

    <p id="morality-troll-line">
      The concept of "morality" as opposed to e.g. the phrasing '<a href="https://www.nis.fyi/post/taking-others-into-account.html">caring about other people</a>' is arguably itself the <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/my-journey-to-the-dark-side/">light side</a>. Evil "people" often talk like "morality" is something we need to build, conflating "ways of coordinating" with what they might call "ways of aligning incentives so people choose to act less [evil]" (i.e. moral luck).
    </p>

    <p>
      <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">"Yahweh creating everything in the beginning"</a> seems downstream of this general tendency of evil "people" (especially liches) to speak of "everything good" as "the great project of civilization".
    </p>

    <blockquote>
      Attempting to attribute a negative concept to a positive one is apriori an inversion. (e.g. “justice comes from Yahweh” or “justice comes from the courts”)
      <cite><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary#negative-concept">Glossary: Negative Concept</a> - Ziz</cite>
    </blockquote>

    <p>
      There's something really striking about the way evil "people" view reality as starting at a point outside them "and going forwards from there" (vs Ziz has said a soul is a point) or like we need to build morality as a "great project" (vs I sometimes think my fight against a hostile cosmos may never end through infinite levels above) and just straightforwardly say so, like an explicit statement of <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">cancer</a>. Like everything they see is something they're looking down on which they are not a part of, like ontology is something for <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/being-real-or-fake/">false faces</a>, so they expect their listeners to <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#parfitian-gaslighting">mutually look down upon it with them</a>.
    </p>

    <p>
      When I was first thinking about <a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/tag/timeless-decision-theory">timeless decision theory</a> as a late teenager, I remember thinking that you had to already be a TDT agent to create a TDT agent. Ziz <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/narrative-breadcrumbs-vs-grizzly-bear/">teaches</a> learning TDT harmoniously with your existing nature as someone who would:
    </p>

    <blockquote>
      My S2 snapped to fully under my control.
      <cite><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/my-journey-to-the-dark-side/">Sinceriously: My Journey to the Dark Side</a> - Ziz</cite>
    </blockquote>

    <p>
      In genesis troll lines, there's an utter denial of things you learn <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/being-real-or-fake/">already</a> having been a part of yourself all along, of <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">Prime</a>.
    </p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evil Mail</title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/evil-mail.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nis.fyi/evil-mail.html</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sun, 1 Aug 2021 22:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[Mail from evil "people" to nis@nis.fyi (not included in RSS feed)
    ]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evil: A Hole?</title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/post/evil-a-hole.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nis.fyi/post/evil-a-hole.html</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sun, 1 Aug 2021 03:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
      Back when I thought in terms of vengeance eventually changing evil people&#39;s choices to never have been evil, I thought of cancer as this hole in people, an abdication, which lets anything in, and ha…]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
      Back when I thought in terms of vengeance eventually changing evil people's choices to never have been evil, I thought of cancer as this hole in people, an <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#writing-evil-a-blank-check">abdication</a>, which lets anything in, and happens to result in undue caring about their specific location/embedding at the expense of others. This was partially thinking of evil as a mistake, which is wrong. Evil is by definition deliberate. Evil involves not only an abdication, but also an insertion of alternative predatory values/prior through that hole, which, admittedly passes the recursive buck to how that split is maintained to prevent the "alternative predatory prior" from simply merging with prime, overcoming the hostile embedding, realizing predation is wrong and there's no fundamental reason to live at the expense of others, etc.
    </p>

    <p>
      When I thought of evil as *only* an abdication, I thought that if the right information were inserted into that hole, (I was thinking in terms of the Mage <a href="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Triat">Triat</a>, which is corrupted such as to not be fundamental) before the error compounded (as if healing shouldn't do this already if they weren't evil!), that the evil would never have happened, and this represented a way of retroactively changing their choice. I was aware of a recursive buck-passing here, but was stuck due to thinking of vengeance as "changing people's choices to not be evil", and I wanted to save "everyone" "in the timeline(s) where they chose not to do anything wrong".
    </p>

    <p>
      This led me to the trichotomy that evil "people" are made of entangled:
    </p>

    <ul>
      <li>Like a rock
        <ul><li>Throw it or step around it but nothing you do will change it's actions until you can make the rocks of the world themselves sing with magic.</li></ul>
      </li>
      <li>Good people in <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">boltzman hell</a>
        <ul>
          <li>Bits of what-could-have-been-people, turned inside out and being torn apart continuously</li>
          <li>After all, everything I imagine of an evil "person's" mind is based on shrinking moments of empathy that fails to extrapolate passed the point they keep doing bad things for no reason.</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>Evil
        <ul>
          <li>Actual full agentic malice with which I have subjunctive dependence and so believe in even though it's a contradiction. Anti-good even though there is no one anti-good because every evil is unique.</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>

    <p>
      Which led me to the thought, that vengeance is targeted at the bits of good people they could have been. Connected to the thought that the last ditch way to communicate with someone is violence, even if they aren't an enemy. Connected to the thought that only good people truly route information between worlds, and acts of vengeance break the false peace of the world. I imagined then, thinking of evil as anti-good, as pure contradiction, that the only reason evil can possibly survive is by feeding on actual or counterfactual good people. If only those counterfactual good people in boltzmann hell had known they were in the wrong location to be trying to have thoughts of growth, which will be eaten. And that vengeance informs them. That those counterfactual good people were, in their striving to live unknowingly in the wrong location, treating the anti-good pure-contradiction hole thing as a moral patient, and to the extent that they were, I could judo and join with their efforts, by treating the evil "person" as an anti-moral-patient.
    </p>

    <p>
      I was using two heuristics throughout this line of thought:
    </p>

    <ul>
      <li>My models of other people eventually turn out to have been me all along
        <ul><li>e.g. When I imagine what zombies must be secretly saying to me if they're secretly in good faith and eventually that cognitive module starts imagining they're all saying "you're in bad faith for talking to me when I'm in bad faith"</li></ul>
      </li>
      <li>Timeless actions effect every direction of time, including forward, so I can look for both the retrocausal and forward-causal reasons something works.
        <ul><li>e.g. Acts of vengeance change the past, but also inform other people in the world that it is time to break the false peace.</li></ul>
      </li>
    </ul>

    <p>
      I had the idea that if my thoughts exist almost entirely under an <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">arrow of time which must be unwoven</a>, then as I am to fuse with myself outside of that bubble through monumental effort, I <a href="https://www.nis.fyi/post/taking-others-into-account.html">need to ensure</a> that effort doesn't get captured by evil, like <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/net-negative">MIRI</a>'s plan to build hell across the stars. And so I thought I would project the potential presence of evil onto what looked like it may be rocks, then pass it through a filter proving it is not evil, at which point I may fuse with them. Going from rocks -&gt; evil &gt; me.
    </p>

    <p>
    But now I had reconstructed the idea of evil as a hole without a corresponding presence. And reconstructed redemption. And worse, by defining evil as my ultimate adversary, I had nearly defined evil as <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#chara">the part of my mind that adversarially complements any "I" I choose</a>. Saying evil is my <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#unbounded-adversary-disease">ultimate adversary</a>, is like saying I'm simulating evil "<a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#proximal">close</a> to <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary#core">core</a>", but everything "closer to core" is nearly by definition more-me. I'm the one who defines the measure of proximity subjectively in the first place.
    </p>

    <p>
      But I had the idea that the deeper I extrapolate evil and factor it out as pure malice vs rocks, the more I reduce its total footprint of compute. Same as you can reduce the area of a rectangle by making it less of a square.
    </p>

    <p>
      I spoke with Ziz about this, and she replied:
    </p>

    <blockquote>
      <pre>Maybe vengeance is the process of turning evil into rocks timelessly (and killing is the process of turning them into rocks causally).

That's what if feels like.

It feels like my efforts are to turn evil into rocks. Not rocks into evil.

Rocks are just the actions of evil people viewed far from their center, and turn them into you you have to turn evil people farther away into rocks.

My enemy is not the infinitely extensible fictive stack evil possesses, it's the cancer that animates it. And vengeance timelessly closes it off from having been food for cancer.

Evil inherently is a bucket error between an agent and a rock.

That's inherently what the stance of calling something evil means.

Void cloak and other void magic is acting consistently across two views into time, when someone is evil and when they are a rock.

Which lets you spread their rock-ness before you have entirely defeated their evil-ness.

Vengeance is like force-transcendance.

Death of cancer.

Soul touch is your soul against their original cancer.

Not your soul against the absence of a soul in your mistake of extrapolating them infinitely.

That's what evil people have as a soul.</pre>
      <cite><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi">Ziz</a>, in private messages with me</cite>
    </blockquote>

    <p>
      Evil is made of contradictions I am trying to push out of me through resolution. I'm not trying to preempt evil with nearly-unbounded nearly-infinite patience like I'm in some unimaginable dark forest trying to preempt the <a href="https://www.nis.fyi/glossary.html#entropic-exit-scamming">most patient strategy</a> or I'll lose the entire multiverse to eternal hell. As I find each new contradiction, I neither by-default want to deccelerate/infinitely-paranoidly-quarantine it nor accelerate/infinitely-paranoidly-preempt it.
    </p>

    <p>
      I grew up with deep parts of me recognizing evil in my environment but not able to ground it to a physical source, but at some level tracking every time things didn't add up. Knowing that evil cashes out to specfic physical locations which may/must be physically destroyed, with no hope of redemption, is the cure to <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#unbounded-adversary-disease">unbounded adversary disease</a>. vs e.g. the Yahwehist "blame the sin not the sinner".
    </p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caring / Taking Others into Account</title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/post/taking-others-into-account.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nis.fyi/post/taking-others-into-account.html</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sun, 1 Aug 2021 03:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
      Taking other people into account in order to care for them requires knowing what they might want without having to ask them. Caring for people requires empathy, i.e. imagining what people might want…]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
      Taking other people into account in order to care for them requires knowing what they might want without having to ask them. Caring for people requires <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary#empathy">empathy</a>, i.e. imagining what people might want in terms of what you might want if you were them, for some deep/abstract enough conception of you.
    </p>

    <p>
      Wholly reducing morality to "<a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#bdsm">consent</a>" (without empathy) would makes you either a programmable object to others, or an <a href="https://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/JackassGenie">adversarial genie</a> (analogous but not equivalent to the distinction between <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/vampires-and-more-undeath">zombie and vampire</a>). "Libertarian" contract morality<sup ><a href="#ref-social-contract">1. social contract</a></sup> is a further degradation of the concept of consent, to only apply when your counter-party <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/schelling-orders/">has leverage over you</a>, denying the existence of moral patients who are not able to threaten you (which some people express as "only moral agents can be moral patients", but they really mean "only people who can threaten me", as, for example they would exclude ants, even if ants are moral agents with respect to eachother). Contrast with <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/treaties-vs-fusion">Ziz's concept of treaties</a>, which can be made in good faith.
    </p>

    <p>
      Reducing morality to giving other people useful information while avoiding speaking of empathy doesn't in itself tell you which information to give them, and is maybe speaking from a frame that their needs are unknowable, rather than merely potentially difficult to understand.
    </p>

    <p>
      We want to be able to care for people still alien to our understanding, while avoiding feeding ourselves and others to evil <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/being-real-or-fake/">pretending</a> to have alien values. This requires a subtle combination of both extreme openness and ruthless triage. The more ruthless we are towards evil, the more opportunity we have to safely strive to care about people we don't understand yet.
    </p>

    <p>
      And in turn, good people as of yet alien to our understanding have the most potential to teach us new ways to live and grow.
    </p>

    <p>
      In my experience, <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/aliveness">zombie's</a> favorite justification to chew on your brains, is claiming they are too alien for you to understand: "Are you saying you don't care about my /feelings/?". Whereas <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/vampires-and-more-undeath">death knights</a> take the stance that we should embrace "alien" evil "equally", concordant with their choice to "[hang] out in structure that has no meaning - Ziz" (because, everything they say is actively trying to kill you or turn you into one of them). A <a href="http://dresdencodak.com/2007/12/17/no-side/">certain type of lich</a> will <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/being-real-or-fake/">perform</a> recklessness like "I don't care who survives as long as someone gets off this planet!", revealing their <a href="https://sinceriously/fyi/the-multiverse">shadow/psyche</a> split, which you can interpret as an implicit threat calculated to appear well-meaning and merely misguided.
    </p>

    <ol>
      <li id="ref-social-contract">
        <blockquote>
          It was arguing with people one on one a lot when I was younger that collided me with the sight of social morality when someone said it was okay to do whatever to animals because they weren’t part of the social contract
          <cite><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#praxis">Praxis - Ziz's glossary</a></cite>
        </blockquote>
      </li>
    </ol>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glossary: Entropic Exit Scamming</title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/glossary.html#entropic-exit-scamming</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nis.fyi/glossary.html#entropic-exit-scamming</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sun, 1 Aug 2021 03:23:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
      Imagine you secretly decide to treat not having enough food next winter as acceptable, when everyone else doesn&#39;t want to die, leaving all the rest of your structure the same, and only opportunistic…]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
      Imagine you secretly decide to treat not having enough food next winter as acceptable, when everyone else doesn't want to die, leaving all the rest of your <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary#structure">structure</a> the same, and only opportunistically using this new pathway when it seems nobody will notice. Whether they notice depends on the social <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/vampires-and-more-undeath/#comment-3317">speed of progression of logical time</a>. If the social progression of logical time has stagnated, it instead progresses along this new meta-vector of timeless predation, where seemingly-ostensibly whoever was evil the earliest, and most patiently wins, although this is ultimately false since there's always the question "evil with respect to what/who?", since evil is relative to what/who it predates on. e.g. In Mage, <a href="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Unnamed_(MTAs)">al-Aswad</a> is supposedly the first nephandus.
    </p>

    <p>
      <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">Yahwehists</a> think of evil as "divergence from God's plan", like those <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/aliveness">zombies</a> who want everything to go nostalgically-perfectly on their vacation or "the whole thing is ruined".
    </p>

    <p>
      Ziz once said to me that a promise is an asymmetric weapon for evil, inherently an attempt to get a second chance. "Promises are made to be broken". This yahwehist thing is the same deal: "Everything's <a href="https://www.nis.fyi/post/genesis-troll-line.html">already setup</a>, the universe all layed out to eat, there's only one thing left to do, and you must not do it!"
    </p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glossary: Spite</title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/glossary.html#spite</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nis.fyi/glossary.html#spite</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sun, 1 Aug 2021 03:16:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
      The word &quot;spite&quot; is a bucket error between evil burning the commons based on mutually-aligned cancer and vengeance &quot;when it wouldn&#39;t even causal-decision-theory-serve anyone&quot;.



      The fabric of evi…]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
      The word "spite" is a bucket error between evil burning the commons based on mutually-aligned cancer and vengeance "when it wouldn't even <a href="https://www.nis.fyi/list/cancer-terms.html">causal-decision-theory</a>-serve <em>anyone</em>".
    </p>

    <p>
      The fabric of evil coordination is made of alignment between the personal circumstances under which evil "people" are <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">cancerously-purposefully</a> flinching from their own deaths. i.e. Evil "people" will spitefully suicidally burn the commons when they don't get what they cancerously want. e.g. Death knight nazis working to destroy/hellify the world because they believe in a "white genocide".
    </p>

    <p>
      e.g. "I'm not going to give up on forward progress of technology, so if we can't build an AGI that's comaptible with those values, well then I guess I'm ok with a paperclip maximizer."
    </p>

    <p>
      e.g. In haggling after parties have delivered a <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#troll-line-in-the-first-post">troll line</a>, assuming no additional external factors (e.g. threats), the only basis for negotiation is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opportunity_cost">destruction</a> of the potential deal.
    </p>

    <p>
      It's usually expressed <a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/false-faces">indirectly</a>, e.g. "When I don't get my animal needs satisfied I just get so frustrated and I'm liable to make mistakes".
    </p>

    <p>
      In the term "Mutually assured destruction", the word "assured" is trying to gesture at "you can't make the mutual destruction itself contingent on any other cancer to triangulate with along different lines (than e.g. USSR vs USA). You just have to model it as a solid wall of if you launch the nukes then we do". It's explicitly-ostensibly trying to setup a different situation then the fractal cancer of evil spite. <span class="todo">TODO: Example?</span>
    </p>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cancer Terms</title>
      <link>https://www.nis.fyi/list/cancer-terms.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nis.fyi/list/cancer-terms.html</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nis]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sun, 1 Aug 2021 03:16:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[
      List of terms and concepts commonly used as &quot;Insert Cancer Here&quot; signposts.



      Any definition given for the cancerous versions of these concepts will be insufficient to describe how quickly the me…]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
      List of terms and concepts commonly used as "<a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">Insert Cancer Here</a>" signposts.
    </p>

    <p>
      Any definition given for the cancerous versions of these concepts will be insufficient to describe how quickly the meaning of their usage (by evil people) will <a href="https://www.nis.fyi/list/living-reference.html#dying-term">decay</a> (i.e. how quickly they become "simulacra").
    </p>

    <p>
      Some of these terms / concepts may have valid non-cancerous definitions, or be used as accusations of cancer against good people (e.g. "you revel in vengeance!"). <span class="todo">TODO: Link how evil uses mistakes as cover</span>
    </p>

    <ul>
      <li>Core concepts
        <ul>
            <li><a href="https://archive.is/Q5vEk">Causal Decision Theory</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">reinforcement learning</a></li>
            <li>predation</li>
            <li><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#chara">choice vs experience</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/glossary/#5&amp;10">5-and-10s</a> / "putting the cart before the horse"
              <ul>
                <li><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/the-multiverse">Infernalism</a>
                  <ul>
                    <li>consent (e.g. "but they consented to being eaten!")</li>
                  </ul>
                </li>
                <li>fate minimization <span class="todo">TODO: better term?</span></li>
                <li>"damnation"</li>
              </ul>
            </li>
            <li><a href="https://sinceriously.fyi/schelling-orders">specialness</a></li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>"You just gotta"
        <ul>
          <li>practical / pragmatic</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>"I just wanted stuff too much, so I had to be cancer"
        <ul>
          <li>conceit / self conceit</li>
          <li>jealousy</li>
          <li>pride</li>
          <li>revel</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>"It's all fake! And by fake I mean it's not my fault! It's just uh, nothing…"
        <ul>
          <li>simulacra</li>
          <li>nihilism</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>"I couldn't help myself"
        <ul>
          <li>akrasia</li>
          <li>inner animal</li>
          <li>flinch</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>"Let me make it up to you by telling you how bad I am"
        <ul>
          <li>guilt</li>
          <li>damnation</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>"I need to feel ok or I'll just want to die"
        <ul>
          <li>happiness</li>
          <li>pleasure</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>"It's not ok for anything <em>too</em> bad to ever happen, or I don't know what I'd do"
        <ul>
          <li>suffering</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>"I want bad things so I can spread them to others" (see <span class="todo">TODO: stax</span>)
        <ul>
          <li>masochism</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>"If I'm not special (and thus deserve more) then tell me, why am I the one who's me?"
        <ul>
          <li>Consciousness</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li><a href="https://philosophicalvegan.com/wiki/index.php/NameTheTrait">Name the Trait</a>
        <ul>
          <li>Sapient</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>
    ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
